<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on julienchastang</title>
    <link>https://julienchastang.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on julienchastang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://julienchastang.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>For Security Purposes, Regularly Expunge Your macOS Clipboard</title>
      <link>https://julienchastang.com/post/pbcopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>

      <guid>https://julienchastang.com/post/pbcopy/</guid>
      <description>I was recently surprised to find some sensitive information in my macOS clipboard that I must have unintentionally copied there earlier. This information could accidentally leak out as a result of an unfortunate or inadvertent paste in a shared Google Doc, for example. Moreover, there is an abundance of information on the Internet concerning clipboards as hacking attack vectors.
As result, I have added the following entry to my crontab:</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Books I Read in 2020</title>
      <link>https://julienchastang.com/post/books-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>

      <guid>https://julienchastang.com/post/books-2020/</guid>
      <description>2020 was not quite the year I had hoped for in terms of reading or blogging. Anyway, here is my reading list for the last year:
 The Snowflake by Kenneth Libbrecht The Columbian Exchange: Biological and Cultural Consequences of 1492 by Alfred W. Crosby Matilda by Roald Dahl (I read a French translation of this book with my daughter.) Littérature française  Le Comte de Monte-Cristo (~1500 pages!) by Alexandre Dumas Les Liaisons Dangereuses by Pierre Choderlos de Laclos Le Père Goriot by Honoré de Balzac La Chartreuse de Parme by Stendhal    Let&amp;rsquo;s hope life can get back to normal in 2021.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Books I Read in 2019</title>
      <link>https://julienchastang.com/post/books-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>

      <guid>https://julienchastang.com/post/books-2019/</guid>
      <description> Ishi, Last of His Tribe by Theodora Kroeber Ancient Walls: Indian Ruins of the Southwest by Chuck Place Very Short Introductions (Oxford University Press):  Anthropocene by Erle C. Ellis The Scientific Revolution by Lawrence M. Principe Galaxies by John Gribbin Voltaire by Nicholas Cronk   French Literature  Bel Ami by Guy De Maupassant Une Vie by Guy De Maupassant Les Miserables (Tomes I-V, ~2000 pages!) by Victor Hugo Notre Dame de Paris by Victor Hugo Vingt Mille Lieues Sous Les Mers by Jules Verne    </description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Join lines, vi-style in Emacs</title>
      <link>https://julienchastang.com/post/join-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>

      <guid>https://julienchastang.com/post/join-lines/</guid>
      <description>I mostly edit in Emacs but occasionally I like to use vi. vi is often the only editor available in certain computing environments. In Emacs, I find myself missing vi&amp;rsquo;s join line capability. Emacs&#39; closest equivalent is M-^ or the unintuitively named delete-indentation function. M-^ is awkward in that it joins the current line to the previous line. This behavior feels unnatural especially when joining many lines in succession where you have to go to the end of the block you want to join and repeatedly type M-^.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Extending Emacs rgrep for Org Mode Only Search</title>
      <link>https://julienchastang.com/post/rgrep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>

      <guid>https://julienchastang.com/post/rgrep/</guid>
      <description>I recently wanted to extend emacs rgrep to search within org files only. Here is what I came up with:
(defun jc/rgrep-org (regexp dir) &amp;#34;rgrep for org files only&amp;#34; (interactive (progn (grep-compute-defaults) (let* ((regexp (grep-read-regexp)) (dir (read-directory-name &amp;#34;Base directory: &amp;#34; nil default-directory t))) (list regexp dir)))) (rgrep regexp &amp;#34;*.org&amp;#34; dir nil)) Note that in order to get this jc/rgrep-org function to work, I had to study and borrow from the internals of rgrep.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Installing X11 Emacs with homebrew</title>
      <link>https://julienchastang.com/post/x11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>

      <guid>https://julienchastang.com/post/x11/</guid>
      <description>A while back it was decided that X11 support would be removed from homebrew-core. Taking matters into my own hands and in the spirit of OSS, I now maintain my own version for anyone who wants it. On MacOS, you will find homebrew-core in /usr/local/Homebrew/Library/Taps/homebrew/homebrew-core.
Once you have the fork brew reinstall emacs --with-x11.
I only occasionally maintain that branch so if you want something more up-to-date, be sure to rebase against homebrew-core/master.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Migrating Blog to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://julienchastang.com/post/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>

      <guid>https://julienchastang.com/post/blog/</guid>
      <description>Revamping this site. More to come hopefully.</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
